[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[all] Ow, ow, ow!
[所有人] 哎哟，哎哟，哎哟！
Okay, if we can't agree on what we're gonna do for our history assignment,
好吧，如果我们不能就历史作业的内容达成一致，
can we at least agree on letting go of each other's hair?
我们至少可以同意放开彼此的头发吧？
[all] Ahh.
[所有人] 啊。
Aw, it's over.
哎，结束了。
I liked the "owing."
我喜欢那个“哎哟”。
- Juice me, Lucy.
- 给我果汁，露西。
What if we do our assignment on the Declaration of Independence?
如果我们把作业做在独立宣言上怎么样？
Did they have cool mustaches back then?
那时候他们有酷酷的胡子吗？
Why would that matter?
那有什么关系？
Because during our presentation, I wanna wear a cool mustache
因为在我们的演讲中，我想戴一个酷酷的小胡子
I can twirl and say things like,
我可以捻着胡子说，
"Mwah-ha-ha-ha-ha!"
“姆瓦-哈-哈-哈-哈-哈！”
And I'm going to cook a historically appropriate dish
我还会准备一道历史时期适宜的菜肴
to serve the class.
给全班同学品尝。
Happy tums make happy chums.
快乐的胃造就快乐的朋友。
- Yeah, well, guess who's not happy.
是啊，猜猜谁不开心。
This chum.
这位朋友。
Why does Mr. Dexter always group us together for class projects?
为什么德克斯特先生总是把我们分在一组做课堂项目？
I thought we moved past this.
我以为我们已经翻篇了。
- I'll tell you why! - Apparently not.
- 我来告诉你为什么！- 看来还没有。
[sighs] He does it to torture me.
[叹气] 他这么做是为了折磨我。
And what's with those gross little white balls of stuff
还有他嘴角那些恶心的小白球是什么东西？
in the corner of his mouth?
那是什么？
What is it?
奶油奶酪？酸奶？
Cream cheese? Yogurt?
牙--
Toothpa--
嘿，德克斯特老师。
Hey, Mr. Dexter.
手臂浮圈，嗯？要去游泳吗？
Arm floaties, huh? Going swimming?
我要在里面装满汽水，这样就不用在电影院付那些高昂的价格了。
I'm gonna fill them with soda,
我要在里面装满汽水，
so I don't have to pay those outrageous prices at the movies.
这样看电影就不用付那些离谱的价钱了。
[slurping]
（吸吮声）
So swimming... oh, yeah.
所以游泳……哦，是的。
In savings!
在省钱！
Anyhoo, good luck on your assignment.
总之，祝你作业顺利。
And it's yogurt... mostly.
而且这是酸奶……大部分是。
Mwah-ha-ha-ha!
哈哈哈哈！
See? That would have been so much better
看吧？如果他有胡子可以捻的话，
if he had a mustache to twirl.
那会好得多。
Mwah-ha-ha-ha-ha!
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na, hey! ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 呐呐呐呐呐，嘿！ ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling melody]
[口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
[whistling melody]
[口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
♪ Na na na na na-na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ Na na na na na-na, hey! ♪
- ♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na na na na na-na ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
[upbeat music]
So I'm sure you guys haven't picked a topic
for your history assignment... have you?
Of course we have!
We're doing Amelia Earhart's flight over the Atlantic.
She had a lot of determination, that one.
I like a gal with moxie.
So how'd you all agree?
那么你们是怎么达成一致的？
I mean, did you just go with what Natalie wanted to do?
我的意思是，你们是不是就按照娜塔莉的想法做了？
What makes you think they just do what I wanna do?
你怎么会觉得他们就按我的想法做呢？
No reason.
没什么理由。
[knuckles crack]
[手指关节响]
Actually, we all decided together.
实际上，我们是一起决定的。
And my name's Natlee. The "uh" is silent.
而且我的名字是Natlee，那个'uh'是不发音的。
Okay.
好的。
Guys, this is not good.
伙计们，这不太好。
Every group has decided on their topic except us.
除了我们，每个小组都已经选定了他们的主题。
So I'm taking the lead.
那么我来带头。
We are doing the sewing of the first American flag.
我们要做的是缝制第一面美国国旗。
Slow your roll, Betsy Boss.
别急，贝琪老大。
I'm taking the lead.
我来带头。
- I'm taking the lead. - I should be in charge.
- 我来带头。 - 我应该负责。
- You guys, stop! - I'm the oldest!
- 你们，停下！ - 我是最年长的！
[all] Ow!
哎哟！
Hey, kids, wait, wait--hey!
嘿，孩子们，等等，等等——嘿！
What is going on?
这是怎么回事？
- Can't decide on a topic
- 无法决定一个主题
for our stupid history assignment.
我们那愚蠢的历史作业。
- History's not stupid. It's important. - Yeah. - You know the old saying--
- 历史并不愚蠢。它很重要。 - 是的。 - 你知道那句老话——
"Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to...
"那些不从历史中学习的人注定要……
repeat it."
重复它。"
[all] Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to...
[所有人] 那些不从历史中学习的人注定要……
"Repeat it."
"重复它。"
[all] Those who fail to learn from history
[所有人] 那些不从历史中学习的人
are doomed to...
注定要……
"Repeat it."
"重复它。"
[all] Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to...
[所有人] 那些不从历史中学习的人注定要……
- Repeat-- - Tom! - What?
Don't you see what's going on here?
Wh--
Okay, why don't you guys do your report
on something you have in common?
Like the store.
I mean, there's tons of history right here.
Oh, in fact, during the Gold Rush,
this building used to be a bank and a saloon.
Mm-hmm.
Picture it, kids--
想象一下，孩子们——
The year was...um--
那一年是...呃——
1859.
1859年。
1859!
1859年！
It was the time of the pilgrims.
那是朝圣者们的时代。
It was the old Wild West.
那是古老的狂野西部。
It was the time of the old Wild West.
那是古老的狂野西部的时代。
[Tom] Gold miners would come to the bank
[汤姆]淘金者会来到银行
to make their deposits,
进行存款，
then settle in for a sassafras root beer,
然后坐下来喝一杯用黄樟根酿造的啤酒，
perfectly slid to them by a kindly barmaid,
由一位友善的女招待完美地递给他们，
enjoy a nice hard candy, some old-timey music,
享受一些美味的硬糖，伴随着一些老式音乐，
which to them was new-timey,
对他们来说却是新奇的，
and maybe even share a stick of a good friend's licorice.
甚至可能分享一根好友的甘草棒。
[snoring]
（打呼声）
I got this.
我搞定这个。
- Wake up! - Aah!
— 醒醒！ — 啊！
You're welcome.
不客气。
Come on. There's learning to do.
快点，还有学习要做。
Follow us.
跟我们来。
I bet you also didn't know
我打赌你也不知道
that our office used to be a bank vault,
我们的办公室曾经是一个银行金库，
and it was the site of the downfall
而且这里是
of a notorious gang.
一个臭名昭著的帮派的覆灭之地。
They were known as the Sugar Beet Gang.
他们被称为甜菜帮。
Maybe you should do your assignment on them.
也许你应该写关于他们的作业。
[Dicky] Wait--you really want us to do our report
[Dicky] 等等——你真的想让我们
on the least cool-sounding gang ever?
写关于听起来最不酷的帮派的报告吗？
This wouldn't be happening
如果当初你让我负责，
if you would have just let me be in charge.
这一切就不会发生了。
I should have been in charge.
我本应该负责的。
- Yeah, right! - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 是啊，没错！ - 哇，哇，哇！
Again with the arguing?
又吵起来了？
When are you kids gonna learn to work together?
你们什么时候才能学会合作？
Your father's right.
你父亲说得对。
You're staying in here
你们要待在这里
until you figure something out.
直到你们想出办法。
Your mother's right.
你母亲说得对。
I am right.
我是对的。
Now, get to work.
现在，开始工作。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
Wait--did you just lock them in?
等等——你刚才是把他们锁在里面了吗？
Oh, don't worry, Anne.
哦，别担心，安妮。
I have the combination... in my wallet.
我有密码组合...在我的钱包里。
How are you gonna find it in this mess?
你在这堆乱七八糟的东西里怎么找得到？
I...have a system.
我...有一个系统。
I just need to find the piece of paper
我只需要找到那张
I wrote the system on.
我写有系统的纸。
Listen, I don't wanna be in here all day,
听着，我不想在这里待一整天，
so we might as well see what this so-called gang is about.
所以我们不妨看看这个所谓的帮派到底是怎么回事。
Eew! All these words are coming off on my hands.
哎呀！这些字都印到我手上了。
Why did they used to make the internet out of paper?
他们以前为什么用纸来做互联网？
Huh. It says here they were called, "The Sugar Beet Gang"
哈。这里说他们被称为，“甜菜帮”
because they chewed on sugar beets,
因为他们嚼甜菜根，
which gave them horrible, rotted teeth.
这让他们有了可怕的、腐烂的牙齿。
Oh, and look! They were siblings!
哦，看！他们是兄弟姐妹！
And their last name was Harper.
而且他们的姓是哈珀。
You think they could be related to us?
你觉得他们和我们有关系吗？
Well, their names were Nikko, Rikko, Dikko, and Deb.
嗯，他们的名字是尼科、里科、迪科和黛布。
So I'm thinking... perhaps.
所以我在想...可能吧。
- And according to my hand,
- 根据我的手相显示，
they were also "bank sobbers."
他们还是“银行哭泣者”。
Why would they cry in a bank?
他们为什么会在银行里哭呢？
It's robbers, Dicky. They were bank robbers!
他们是劫匪，迪基。他们是银行劫匪！
You can say it as loud as you want,
你可以大声说出来，
but that still doesn't explain the crying.
但这仍然解释不了他们为什么哭。
- And their first and only bank robbery
- 而且他们的第一次也是唯一一次银行抢劫
happened right here.
就发生在这里。
[ragtime piano music]
[拉格泰姆钢琴音乐]
♪ ♪
- What are you doing? - Stop it!
- 你在干什么？ - 住手！
Nikko, Rikko, Dikko, quit your horseplay!
尼科，里科，迪科，别胡闹了！
Sorry, Pa.
对不起，爸爸。
Lookin' awful purdy today, Maebel.
今天看起来真漂亮，梅贝尔。
You sayin' I don't look purdy, Dikko?
你是说我看起来不漂亮吗，迪科？
[knuckles crack]
[指节响]
No, no, you're purdy too, Natabel!
不，不，你也漂亮，纳塔贝尔！
Hey, Ma, Pa, can you get us some real candy
嘿，妈妈，爸爸，你们能给我们买点真正的糖果吗？
like all them other kids?
像其他所有孩子那样的？
Now, Deb, you know money don't grow on trees.
现在，黛布，你知道钱不是长在树上的。
But as farmers, if it did,
但如果我们农民能种出钱来，
we'd sure as heck plant some.
我们肯定会种一些。
And you know me and Pa's been saving up
你也知道我和爸爸一直在攒钱
to buy some new farmin' tools.
为了买一些新的农具。
I wish we was rich.
我真希望我们很有钱。
Well, we ain't, so go on now
但我们不是，所以现在去吧
and eat up on them sugar beets we done grew for ya.
吃掉我们为你种的甜菜。
[kids groaning]
[孩子们抱怨]
I got this.
我来搞定。
Eat your beets!
吃你的甜菜！
You're welcome.
不客气。
[spits] [clang]
呸！[金属撞击声]
Oops. That there was another tooth!
哎呀，又是一颗牙！
Yee-haw! That means I got the most left.
耶！这意味着我剩下的最多。
I'm winning by a tooth!
我以一颗牙的优势领先！
[clang]
[金属撞击声]
[all] Aw!
哎！
Look here, Lil Squershy lost his first tooth.
看，小胆怯掉了第一颗牙。
[laughs]
哈哈！
That's the sheriff!
那是警长！
Why does he always have that white stuff in his mustache?
为什么他总是胡子上有那种白色的东西？
What is it, buttermilk?
是什么，酪乳吗？
Porridge, tapioca?
粥，西米？
Well, well, well!
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀！
If it isn't the Harpers and their toothless sugar brats!
这不是哈珀一家和他们那些没牙的小糖鬼吗！
[goat bleating]
[山羊叫声]
Quit your complaining, Suzie! I'll be right out!
别抱怨了，苏西！我马上出来！
Are you riding a goat, Sheriff?
你在骑山羊吗，警长？
Well, she's a loaner. My horse is in the shop.
哦，她是个临时借来的。我的马在店里。
[bleating]
[山羊叫声]
She's awful mouthy for a loaner, though.
尽管她作为借来的羊话有点多。
And it's goat's milk...
而且这是山羊奶……
mostly.
大部分是。
Out of my way, you filthy Harpers!
让开，你们这些肮脏的哈珀家的人！
Let someone with a real deposit through!
让真正有存款的人通过！
I just struck gold!
我刚刚挖到金子了！
A-gi-gi-gi-gi-gi!
啊-gi-gi-gi-gi-gi！
See all that gold?
看到所有那些金子了吗？
Sure do.
当然看到了。
Come here, y'all.
过来，大家。
Y'all thinking what I'm thinking?
你们是不是在想我所想的事？
Well, if you're thinking what the clouds taste like,
嗯，如果你在想云朵是什么味道，
then we're thinkin' the same thinkin'.
那我们就是在想同一件事。
No, I ain't!
不，我不是！
I'm thinkin' we steal that gold
我在想我们偷走那些金子
and get Ma and Pa the farm tools they been wanting.
然后给爸妈买他们一直想要的农具。
All right, but if there's anything left over,
好吧，但如果还有剩下的，
we're getting us a hot air balloon
我们要买一个热气球
and doing us some cloud tastin'!
然后去尝尝云朵的味道！
Oh, so they weren't bad kids.
哦，所以他们不是坏孩子。
They just wanted to help their parents.
他们只是想帮助他们的父母。
What happened next?
接下来发生了什么？
Yeah, I never thought
是的，我从没想过
I'd say this, but... keep reading!
我会这么说，但是...继续读！
Okay...
好的...
Oh, man, when we get that gold,
哦，伙计，当我们拿到那笔黄金时，
I'm gonna buy me one of them sassafras floats.
我要给自己买一个那种黄樟木的浮筒。
All right. I'll add it to the list.
好吧。我会把它加到清单上。
Farm tools, cloud tasting, sassafras.
农具，云品尝，黄樟木。
Anything else?
还有别的吗？
I could use some new boots.
我需要一双新靴子。
Me too.
我也是。
Same here.
Sorry to interrupt the toe-down,
抱歉打断一下，
but get your toes down.
但你们得集中注意力。
I been busy making a map.
我一直在忙着制作地图。
We just need to figure out how to get
我们只需要想办法
from here to here without anyone noticing.
从这里到那里而不被任何人发现。
What if I fire up a batch of my spicy three-bean chili,
如果我做一批我的辣味三豆辣椒，
chow it down, and blow everyone outta here?
吃掉它，然后把所有人都赶走怎么样？
Where are we gonna get our hands on three beans?
我们上哪儿弄三种豆子？
I mean, you got two, at best.
我是说，你最多只有两种。
Then add a third bean to the list!
那就再加一种豆子到清单上！
Stop spending bean money you ain't got yet!
别花你还没赚到的豆子钱！
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的交谈声]
Oh, would y'all just hush?
哦，你们能不能安静点？
Everyone's lookin'!
大家都在看呢！
Hey... that gives me an idea.
嘿... 这给了我一个主意。
Come on over for one of our circle gatherings.
来参加我们的圆圈聚会吧。
All right.
好吧。
We're gonna sneak Nikko into that there vault.
我们要悄悄地把Nikko带进那个保险库。
All we need to do is create a distraction.
我们只需要制造一个干扰。
And I know just how to do it.
而且我知道该怎么做。
Candy saloon fight!
糖果酒吧打斗！
[ragtime piano music]
[拉格泰姆钢琴音乐]
♪ ♪
- Gi-gi-gi-gi!
- Gi-gi-gi-gi！
[bleating]
[咩咩叫]
[Dawn] "Later that night, with Nikko now in the vault,
[Dawn] 那天晚上晚些时候，Nikko现在在保险库里，
"he was able to let the others in,
他能够让他们进来，
so they could get away with the gold."
这样他们就能带着金子逃走了。
- Our plan is working!
我们的计划成功了！
Mwah-ha-ha-ha-ha!
哈哈哈哈哈！
- The boy ain't wrong. - Hmm.
那小子说得没错。 - 嗯。
[all] Mwah-ha-ha-ha-ha!
哈哈哈哈哈！
Wow, Deb's plan worked.
哇，Deb的计划成功了。
Or did it?
还是失败了？
According to this,
根据这个，
the sheriff busted them in the bank that night
那天晚上警长在银行抓到了他们，
and the gold was never found!
而金子至今下落不明！
It could be buried right here in the store!
它可能就埋在这家店里！
[all] Whoa!
[所有人] 哇！
And supposedly, there's even a map!
而且据说，还有一张地图！
Which means we could be rich!
这意味着我们可能会变得富有！
We gotta find that map!
我们必须找到那张地图！
"Expired coupon for free yogurt from...
“2003年的免费酸奶优惠券...”
2003?"
2003年？
They'll honor that.
他们会承认这个的。
Tom, did you find the combination yet?
汤姆，你找到密码了吗？
No, but good news!
没有，但好消息！
I finally made it through this wallet.
我终于翻完了这个钱包。
How is that good news?
这算什么好消息？
Because it means the combo's gotta be in...
因为这意味着组合一定在……
this one!
这个里面！
You have two wallets?
你有两个钱包？
You have 26 purses, Anne!
安妮，你有26个手袋！
We've looked everywhere.
我们已经找遍了所有地方。
There's no map--dang it!
没有地图——该死！
It's the map!
是地图！
And I'm in charge of it.
而且我负责保管它。
No, I knocked it out from behind the plaque.
不，我是从牌匾后面把它打出来的。
I should be in charge.
我应该负责。
No, I should!
不，我应该！
None of you even know how to read a map.
你们中没有一个人知道怎么读地图。
You don't read a map. You just look at it!
你不是读地图，你只是看它！
[all grunting]
（所有人哼哼）
Great! Now look what you've done!
太好了！现在看看你们做了什么！
[thinking] [gasps] I have the X!
（思考）（吸气）我有X标记！
If I find the treasure,
如果我找到宝藏，
I could buy a year's supply of sweater-vests!
我就能买一年的毛衣背心了！
Don't look suspicious.
别看起来可疑。
[thinking] I have the X!
我在想，我有那个X！
I could buy hundreds of beans for my chili!
我可以为我的辣椒买几百颗豆子！
Don't look suspicious.
别看起来可疑。
[thinking] Those are Ricky and Nicky's suspicious faces.
我在想，那是Ricky和Nicky的可疑表情。
Maybe they know I have the X.
也许他们知道我有那个X。
Look natural.
看起来自然点。
[thinking] Dawn looks really natural right now.
我在想，Dawn现在看起来真的很自然。
Oh, hey, I got the X!
哦，嘿，我拿到了那个X！
Look as natural as Dawn.
要像Dawn那样自然。
So you guys wanna just leave and not say why?
所以你们就想这么走了，不说原因？
- Yep. - Sure.
- 是的。 - 当然。
See ya.
再见。
You don't know the combination,
你不知道密码，
and you have no idea what you're doing.
而且你完全不知道自己在做什么。
Shh! I need quiet so I can hear the clicks.
嘘！我需要安静，这样我才能听到咔嗒声。
Oh! I hear something.
哦！我听到什么了。
- Oh, oh! - Oh, oh!
- 哦，哦！ - 哦，哦！
[Tom, muffled] Hmm. I guess it opens from the inside.
[汤姆，含糊] 嗯。我猜是从里面开的。
[Anne, muffled] Good to know.
[安妮，含糊] 这倒是挺好的。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
So you guys wanna just go our separate ways and not say why?
所以你们是想各走各的路，不解释原因吗？
- Yep! - Sure.
- 是的！ - 当然。
See ya!
再见！
[rapid old-timey music]
[快速的怀旧音乐]
[beeping]
[哔哔声]
[sustained beep]
[持续的哔声]
[hollow thunk]
[空洞的撞击声]
Ohh.
哦。
[old-timey music resumes]
[怀旧音乐继续]
♪ ♪
[clattering]
[叮当声]
♪ ♪
[thud, thump]
[砰砰声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Ah.
啊。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
You guys had X's too, huh?
你们也有X标记，是吧？
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 是的。 - 是的。
Did you guys find anything?
你们找到什么了吗？
- No. - No!
- 没有。 - 没有！
[all] [gasp] Ricky!
[所有人] [惊呼] 瑞奇！
Tom, did you finally clean out your wallets
汤姆，你终于清理了你的钱包
like we talked about?
就像我们讨论的那样？
Ha. It's no longer wallets, Anne.
哈。不再是钱包了，安妮。
Papa Tom got it down to just...
爸爸汤姆把它减少到了...
one.
一个。
So the only thing you threw away
所以你唯一扔掉的东西
was your second wallet?
是你的第二个钱包？
Oh, no, no, no, it's in there! Huh?
哦，不，不，不，它在里面！嗯？
Papa Tom found a way...
爸爸汤姆找到了一个方法...
to fit one wallet...
把一个钱包...
inside the other.
塞进另一个里面。
Gah!
啊！
- Honey? - Yeah.
- 亲爱的？ - 嗯。
- I say this with love... - Mm-hmm.
- 我是带着爱说的... - 嗯哼。
But, um, I think you have a wallet problem.
但是，呃，我觉得你有钱包问题。
Pfft. I do not.
噗。我没有。
There's plenty of room in this thing.
这里面还有很多空间。
I can still fit a... ton of stuff in here.
我还能放一堆东西进去。
[creaking]
[嘎吱声]
Papa Tom has a problem, Anne.
安妮，爸爸汤姆有问题。
- All right, where's the gold?
- 好吧，金子在哪儿？
We know you found it!
我们知道你找到了！
Look at him.
看看他。
He's probably already buying a sweater-vest
他可能已经在为一年中的每一天买一件毛衣背心了。
for every day of the year.
我打赌是羊绒的！
I bet it's cashmere!
首先，我不会选择羊绒。
First of all, I wouldn't do cashmere.
我会选一件优质的美利奴羊毛。
I'd go with a nice merino wool.
它不会起球，而且你也不用付干洗费。
It doesn't pill, and you don't have
它不会起球，而且你也不需要
to pay for dry cleaning.
支付干洗费用。
Then again, if I found the gold, I'd be rich,
不过话说回来，如果我找到了金子，我就会变得富有，
and dry cleaning expenses wouldn't matter.
干洗费用也就不重要了。
So you're right, Nicky. Cashmere.
所以你是对的，Nicky。羊绒。
So you did or didn't find the gold?
那么你到底有没有找到金子？
Didn't. Otherwise, I'd be ordering cashmere.
没有。否则我就会订购羊绒了。
There was nothing under my X,
我的X下面什么都没有，
so I came back to do more research,
所以我回来做更多的研究，
and I found out what went wrong with the Sugar Beet Gang
然后我发现糖甜菜帮在抢劫那晚出了什么问题。
the night of the robbery.
抢劫当晚。
- All right, let's grab the gold and git!
- 好了，我们拿了金子就走！
Hold up. You ain't in charge.
等等。你不是老大。
Now, let's grab the gold and git.
现在，我们拿了金子就走。
I just said that!
我刚说了！
I said it better.
我说得更好。
Come on, now,
来吧，现在，
let's just grab the gold and git.
我们就拿了金子走。
I said it the best.
我说的最好。
The secret is to really hit the "git."
关键是要真正做到‘走’。
You think you hit the git?
你以为你做到了？
Watch me hit the git.
看我做给你看。
Let's grab the gold and leave!
我们拿了金子就走！
Oh. I forgot the git.
哦，我忘了关键一步。
You always forget the git!
你总是忘记关键步骤！
[overlapping yelling]
（重叠的喊叫声）
[thud]
（砰的一声）
Shh, shh!
嘘，嘘！
Y'all hear that?
你们听到了吗？
Someone's here!
有人来了！
- It's probably the sheriff. - It's not the sheriff.
- 可能是警长。 - 不是警长。
[goat bleats]
[山羊叫声]
[all] It's the sheriff!
[所有人] 是警长！
Now we done it!
这下我们完了！
By all this arguing, we wasted all our git-away time!
通过这些争吵，我们浪费了所有逃跑的时间！
Hold up!
等等！
You ain't never gonna get past that sheriff with all that gold.
你带着那么多金子，永远也过不了警长那关。
We're gonna have to hide it and come back for it later.
我们得把它藏起来，以后再来取。
Here.
这里。
I say...
我说...
We hide it...here!
我们把它藏在这里！
That's plumb crazy!
这简直是疯了！
I say here.
我说藏在这里。
Hogwash!
胡说八道！
- Here's best. - No, it ain't. Here.
- 这里最好。 - 不，不是这里。这里。
You don't know what you're talking about!
你根本不知道你在说什么！
[overlapping arguing]
[重叠的争吵]
So that's why there's four X's on the map.
所以这就是为什么地图上有四个X标记。
Yeah, but how come there was no gold
是的，但为什么在这些标记下都没有黄金呢？
under any of them?
也许我们遗漏了什么。
Maybe we're missing something.
Like what?
比如什么？
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
This big giant X in the middle!
这个中间的大大的巨型X！
- Whoa! - Whoa!
哇！
Guess without all four pieces,
没有这四块拼图，
we would have never found the gold!
我们永远找不到黄金！
And according to this, it's buried right under...
根据这个，它就埋在...下面...
Dad's desk!
爸爸的书桌下！
Guys, in one second, we could be rich.
伙计们，再过一秒，我们可能就发财了。
Come on.
快点。
[all grunting]
[所有人用力]
[Dicky] Oh, we did it!
[迪基]哦，我们做到了！
- Finally. - We're rich!
- 终于。 - 我们发财了！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
So this is what we pulled out of the floor.
这就是我们从地板下挖出来的东西。
[class] Whoa!
[惊叹声]哇！
So how much gold was there?
那到底有多少金子呢？
Because you know the rule: if you bring something in,
因为你知道规则：如果你带了东西进来，
there needs to be enough for everybody.
需要有足够的分给每个人。
Everybody.
每个人。
There was no gold, Mae.
没有黄金，Mae。
[class] Aw!
[class] 啊！
Oh.
哦。
So if there was no gold, what did you find?
既然没有黄金，你们找到了什么？
This.
这个。
Dried-up sugar beets.
干枯的甜菜。
[class] Eew!
[class] 咦！
Is this going somewhere, Harpers?
这有什么用，Harpers？
Yeah. What happened to the real treasure?
是的。真正的宝藏怎么了？
Turns out the Sugar Beet Gang
结果发现，那晚不只是糖甜菜帮在追寻黄金。
weren't the only ones after the gold that night.
那晚不只是糖甜菜帮在追寻黄金。
[overlapping shouting]
（重叠的喊叫声）
Just wait a minute!
等一下！
All this fussin' is for nussin'!
所有这些争吵都是为了什么！
Did she just say "nussin'"?
她刚才是说“什么”吗？
She meant nothin', but she ain't got no teeth left.
她的意思是什么都没有，但她已经没有牙齿了。
These X's ain't no good.
这些叉叉没用。
They're all out where the sheriff is.
他们都跑到警长那里去了。
Here.
这里。
Sometimes the most obvious place
有时候最明显的地方
is the best.
就是最好的。
Get in there.
进去吧。
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
And now for the map...
现在轮到地图了...
And we hide it...
我们把它藏...
here!
在这里！
All right, now, let's hightail it outta here!
好了，现在，我们快离开这里！
- Hold it right there, Sugar Brats!
- 停在那儿，糖宝贝们！
You ain't gonna arrest us, are you, Sheriff?
你不会是要逮捕我们吧，警长？
So not only did the sheriff take their gold,
警长不仅拿走了他们的金子，
but he locked the Sugar Beet Gang up for good.
还把糖萝卜帮彻底关了起来。
But they would have gotten away with it
但他们本可以逃脱的，
if it wasn't for all their fighting.
如果不是因为他们之间的争斗。
That was their downfall.
那是他们的失败之处。
And it was almost ours too.
那几乎也是我们的失败。
But we stopped all our fussin' over nussin',
但我们停止了关于照顾的争吵，
and the four of us got together to finish our project.
我们四个人团结起来完成了我们的项目。
And for the first time in history,
这是历史上第一次，
I actually enjoyed learning about history.
我真的很享受学习历史的过程。
We all did.
我们都是。
I guess the old saying is true.
我想那句老话是真的。
"Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to...
“那些不从历史中学习的人注定要……
[all] Repeat it."
[所有人] 重复它。
[class] Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to...
[班级] 那些不从历史中学习的人注定要……
[all] "Repeat it."
[所有人] “重复它。”
[class] Those who fail to learn from history
[班级] 那些不从历史中学习的人
are doomed to...
注定要……
[all] "Repeat it!"
[所有人] “重复它！”
[class] Those who fail to learn from history
[班级] 那些不从历史中学习的人
are doomed to...
注定要...
[all] "Repeat it!"
[全体] "重蹈覆辙！"
[class shouting] Those who fail to learn
[班级喊叫] 那些不从历史中学习的人
from history are doomed to...
注定要...
[all] "Repeat it!"
[全体] "重蹈覆辙！"
[class] Those who fail to learn from history...
[班级] 那些不从历史中学习的人...
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪